

WILL HOLSTEN FRONT END DEVELOPER

PERSONAL INFO

ADDRESS

Swiss Cottage, London

E-MAIL

mail@willholsten.com

PHONE

+44 (0) 7403 533 961

WEBSITE

willholsten.com

lin

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/willholsten

GITHUB

www.github.com/willholsten

DEV

TOOLS

WEBPACK / GULP HTML CSS / SASS NPM / YARN **JAVASCRIPT** BABEL

REACT GIT **BOOTSTRAP** JIRA

DESIGN

ADOBE CC SKETCH / ZEPLIN

ABOUT ME

I am a graduate from The University of Adelaide with a Bachelor of Design Studies and a passion for UX design and front end development. Having worked in both of these fields for a number of years, I have extensive experience working in multi-functional, agile team environments with a primary focus on eCommerce solutions.

EXPERIENCE

2018-2019 FRONT END DEVELOPER

ID MOBILE (Contract)

Lead front end developer for a complete basket & checkout migration involving global teams and adhering to the requirements of iD Mobile with over 1 million mobile customers.

The project was built in PHP using the Symfony framework with a Docker environment which resulted in rapid development by utilising reusable components.

Built strong relationships with stakeholders, UX designers and back end developers in an agile environment through daily stand ups and thorough Jira/Bitbucket management.

2016-2018

UX DESIGNER / FRONT END DEVELOPER

SURFDOME

Managed the front end codebase for 7 domains including 5 international languages.

Lead UX designer for complete website design overhaul. Working with the UX manager and tech team to produce homepage, PLP, PDP and basket & checkout design improvements.

Designed and developed email marketing newsletters to a subscription group of over 1.2 million customers.

2016-

DIRECTOR, FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

WILLHOLSTEN.COM

Working directly with clients to a mobile first mentality and building intuitive user experiences whilst developing fast, reliable and scalable code with React.

Building and managing domain, cloud hosting and email services. This involved analysing and preventing any down time and providing continual support for clients in the hospitality, B2B and eCommerce sectors.

2009-2011

CO-MANAGER

HOLSTENS

Working in-house in the B2B sector, I was responsible for the product management for over 1000 items.

Lead designer for the current eCommerce website.

General account management, customer service and sales.

EDUCATION

2017

COMPLETE REACT WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSE

UDEMY

React components, React Styling, React-Router, Redux, Jest, Firebase

2016

THE MODERN JAVASCRIPT BOOTCAMP

UDEMY

Asynchronous JavaScript, Data Storage, APIs, Babel, Webpack

2009-2011

BACHELOR OF DESIGN STUDIES

THE UNIVERSITY OF ADELAIDE

Majored in Architecture Studies, Landscape Architecture and Digital Design